



Core Competencies

- Delivery Excellence
- Director Program Management
- Scaled Agile Framework
- Product Management
- Product Development
- Program Management
- Delivery Management
- Project Management
- Agile Methodology
- PMP Trained
- JIRA
- Scrum
- Scrumban
- Kanban
- SAFe
- PSM
- Cloud Computing
- Artificial Intelligence
- Data Warehousing



Technical Skills

- Scrum ,Kanban ,SAFe
- Jira ,TFS ,VersionOne
- Confluence, SharePoint
- Salesforce CPQ
- Scrum ,Kanban, SAFe
- Oracle,MTM,Agile,Junit
- AWS Cloud

Siddhartha Singh

Program Director



16 Years 0 Month



7019524643



Program Director with 16 years in IT industry, specialized in Product Development & Management, Program Delivery Excellence, Release Engineering, AWS Cloud Computing, Agile, Scrum, Lean, SAFe. java, asp.net, SAP, Salesforce, jira, AI, EasyBI, PMP Trained.



Profile Summary

With 1.5 decade into product and application development in the IT industry, I have led multi-milliondollar client accounts in the Financial Service domain, managing teams of 158 members and generating annual revenue of 11 million. I have successfully led 4 large programs in this role, including new Product Development, Support Services, Infra Ops management, and new client onboarding. I have also been responsible for hiring, talent development, and retention at the account level. As a Delivery Lead for new product development, I have orchestrated annual product roadmaps and release plans, provided coaching to ART teams, and reinforced SAFe Framework & Lean-Agile principles at the system level. I have 7+ years of international work exposure, working in the USA at Boeing, and have led globally distributed diverse teams in a virtual environment. In 2022, I acquired an M. Tech degree from BITS Pilani in Software Systems with specialization in Data Analytics.



Education

M.Tech, 2022

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani

B.Tech/B.E., 2007

Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU)

12th, 2001

CBSE, English

10th, 1999

CBSE, English

- Github
- Bitbucket



Personal Information

Date of birth 12-Dec-1984

Gender Male

Address

B 306 Skylark Esta, Hoodi Main Road, Hoodi

City

Bengaluru

Country India



Work Experience

Jan 2022 - Jun 2023

Program Director

Publicis Sapient

- Provided strategic direction and oversight for the product delivery and maintenance function, aligning activities with organizational goals, market trends, and client needs.
- Led a team of product managers, project managers, and delivery specialists in executing product roadmaps, ensuring adherence to timelines, quality standards, and budgetary constraints.
- Implemented best practices and methodologies for product delivery, including Agile, Scrum, and Lean principles, in SAFe framework to optimize workflows, increase efficiency, and foster a culture of continuous improvement and measured them through agile maturity assessments.
- Keeping a track of Program milestones, scope and resources and overall program health and navigating through the Program RISKs, ASSUMPTIONs, ISSUES and DEPENDENCIES using a RAID board.
- Leading the change control board meeting with aim to approve least disruptive changes that has highest cost of delay.
- Collaborated with senior leadership, product development teams, sales, marketing, and customer success departments to define product strategies, prioritize initiatives, and drive go-to-market plans.
- Developed and maintained key performance indicators
 (KPIs) and metrics to track delivery performance, identify
 bottlenecks, and drive data-driven decision-making to
 improve delivery processes.
- Cultivated strong relationships with clients and stakeholders, serving as a trusted advisor and primary point of contact for escalations, feedback, and strategic discussions.
- Spearheaded the development and implementation of scalable processes, tools (Easy BI), and frameworks (SAFe) to enhance delivery capabilities, improve resource allocation, and mitigate project risks.
- Provided mentorship, coaching, and professional development opportunities to team members, fostering a collaborative and high-performance culture along with

performance management and attrition control.

 Managing program finances like revenue, operating margins, direct & indirect cost, tools procurements and license approvals.

Nov 2020 - Dec 2021

Senior Manager

Publicis Sapient

- Spearheaded the end-to-end product delivery process, from conceptualization to launch, for 3 key projects, ensuring alignment with stakeholder expectations, timelines, and budgets.
- Collaborated closely with product development teams, engineering, marketing, and sales departments to define project scopes, objectives, and deliverables.
- Implemented project management methodologies such as Agile and Scrum, facilitating regular stand-up meetings, sprint planning, and retrospectives to enhance team productivity and communication.
- Conducted risk assessments and mitigation strategies to anticipate and address potential project roadblocks, ensuring seamless execution and delivery.
- Fostered a culture of continuous improvement by examining delivery metrics, identifying areas for enhancement, and implementing process optimizations to streamline workflows and drive efficiency gains.
- Acted as a primary point of contact for clients, providing regular project updates, addressing concerns, and managing expectations to ensure high levels of customer satisfaction.
- Led cross-functional globally distributed teams in resolving escalated issues and conflicts, fostering collaboration and maintaining a positive team dynamic throughout the project lifecycle.
- Conducted performance evaluations, provided constructive feedback, and mentored team members to support their professional growth and development in partnership with Learning & Talent Development (L&TD) team and HR.
- Turnaround a highly complex multi-million-dollar infra development project (Data Transport Layer) which was time sensitive and critical for business. Have gone beyond normal and experimented multiple new ways to solve problems and succeeded.

- Curated Agile adoption roadmap and implemented the Agile Scrum framework at account level. Coached, mentored, and developed many high performing teams including Scrum Masters, Product Owners to support digital transformation journey of a global asset management organization present in 25 countries and serving clients in more than 120 countries.
- EXTRA: Driving the PSU (Publicis Sapient University) a global initiative as a PM that has vested interest of our CEO and other top executives.
- Reorganizing PMO org structuring at portfolio level to yield a seamless experience across portfolio and bring standardization and consistency in terms of handling common activities across several accounts.

Dec 2017 - Aug 2020

Project Manager

Boeing

- As Scrum Master / pseudo RTE managed enterprise initiative of implementing SAP ERP in SAFe 4.6 framework.
- Team Leadership, mentoring and coaching agile/scrum methodology to multiple teams.
- Cross-Functional collaboration in globally distributed and diverse environment.
- Risk Management, Process Optimization, Stakeholder Management, Customer Relationship Management, Communication and Presentation Skills
- Problem-Solving and Decision-Making to produce outcome.
- EXTRA: Led Learning Ambassador Program at EMEA
 region while working at Boeing India to spread awareness
 about the learning opportunities made available by the
 organization for the employees which have not been
 utilized well due to lack of awareness.

Jun 2010 - Dec 2017

Product Manager

HCL America Inc.

- Created multi-year Product roadmap and execution strategy with gated review intervals and acceptance checklist.
- Interviewed cross-functional stakeholders for requirement elicitation.
- Performed functional and technical feasibility analysis along with Architects, development team and UX

designers.

- Performed tool capability/limitation analysis before selecting the right tool to be used in the product.
- Performed analysis to precisely estimate the time to launch and time to ROI on various products
- Illustrated Epic, Features and User Stories complied with DoR in tools like TFS and Jira.
- Facilitated the product development decision making with stakeholders, development and UX teams with quick turnaround on clarifications and decision makings.
- Performed Epic, Feature and User story prioritization based on the principle of least cost of delay and maximum value delivered to the business.

Jun 2007 - Jun 2010

Automation Engineer

HCL Technologies Ltd.

 As Automation Engineer, created test scripts, reviewed, and ensured code quality, and provided fix to defects in the code.



Projects

974 Days

2nd Century Enterprise Systems - SAP ERP

Led globally distributed, culturally diverse, and multi-vendor two teams, PI planning and execution using SAFe 4.6 framework, Program performance monitoring, Led project team to setup SAFe 4.6 processes, Led Learning Ambassador Program at EMEA region.

2710 Days

Pricing and Revenue Management System

Interviewed cross-functional stakeholders for requirement elicitation, Performed tool capabilitylimitation analysis, Facilitated the product development decision making, Performed Epic, Feature and User story prioritization.

1096 Days

Miscellaneous Banking Projects

Created test scripts, reviewed, and ensured code quality, provided fix to defects in the code.



Courses & Certifications

- Certified Agile Coach (ICP-ACC)
- Certified SAFe Practitioner 4.6
- Certified SAFe Practitioner 5
- Certified SAFe Agilist
- Certificate in Project Management

- Professional Scrum Master
- Certified SAFe Practitioner (SP) 4.6
- Certified SAFe Practitioner (SP) 5